The days are numbered.
28 Days Later is a horror, thriller, science
fiction film directed by Danny Boyle.
Twenty-eight days after a killer virus was accidentally unleashed from a British research facility, a small group
of London survivors are caught in a desperate struggle to protect themselves from the infected.
Carried by animals and humans, the virus turns those it infects into
homicidal maniacs -- and it's absolutely impossible to contain.
Jim, played by Cillian Murphy.
Selena, played by Naomie Harris.
Frank, played by Brendan Gleeson.
Hannah, played by Megan Burns.
Major Henry West, played by Christopher Eccleston.
Mark, played by Noah Huntley.
28 Days Later (sometimes stylised with an ellipsis as 28 Days Later...) is a 2002 British
post-apocalyptic horror film directed by Danny Boyle and written by Alex Garland.
It stars Cillian Murphy as a bicycle courier who awakens from a coma to discover that the accidental
release of a highly contagious, aggression-inducing virus has caused the breakdown of society.
Naomie Harris, Christopher Eccleston, Megan Burns, and
Brendan Gleeson appear in supporting roles.
Garland took inspiration from George A.
Romero's Night of the Living Dead film series and John
Wyndham's 1951 novel The Day of the Triffids.
Filming took place in various locations in the United Kingdom in 2001.
The crew filmed for brief periods during early mornings and temporarily closed streets to
capture recognisable and typically busy areas when they were deserted.
John Murphy composed an original soundtrack for the film, with
other instrumental songs by Brian Eno, Godspeed You!
Black Emperor, and other artists.
28 Days Later was released on 1 November 2002 in the United Kingdom by Fox
Searchlight Pictures to generally positive reviews and commercial success.
Grossing $82.8 million worldwide on a budget of $8 million, it
became one of the most profitable horror films of 2002.
Reviewers praised Boyle's direction, the cast's performances,
Garland's screenplay, the atmosphere and soundtrack.
Despite Boyle not considering it a zombie film, 28 Days Later is credited with reinvigorating the genre and influencing
a revival in it a decade after its release, with its fast-running infected and character-driven drama.
It has been featured in several "best-of" film lists.
The film's success launched its titular film series, featuring three further installments, 28 Weeks
Later (2007), 28 Years Later (2025), and 28 Years Later: The Bone Temple (2026).
A wider franchise also includes the graphic novel 28 Days Later: The Aftermath
(2007), and the comic book series 28 Days Later (2009–2011).
The film explores themes of daughter, taxi, london,
england, submachine gun, gas station.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.